New York Coalition for Alternatives to Pesticides; Records apap151
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneous Files, 1908-2000; 5; 33.25 cubic ft.
  - Subseries 3: Health Issues from Pesticide / Chemical Use, Undated; 5.3
    - Pesticides / Pregnancy -- Decreased Fertility, 1991-2001 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 64)
    - Pesticides / Pregnancy -- Fetal Death, 2001 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 65)
    - Pesticides / Pregnancy -- Greater Boston Physicians for Social Responsibility and MASSPIRG: "Generations at Risk", Undated (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 66)
    - Pesticides / Pregnancy -- Miscarriages, 2001-2002 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 67)
    - Quotable Quotes [on Pesticide Risks], NYCAP Information Packet, ca. 1997 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 68)
    - Reproductive Health and Pesticides, 1996-2002 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 69)
    - Single Chemical Sensitivity, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 70)
    - Solid Waste Issues, 1991; 1994-1995; Undated (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 71)
    - Special Foods -- For People with Allergies and Chemical Sensitivities, Undated (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 72)
    - State of Children's Health and Environmental 2001, John Wargo and Linda Evenson Wargo, 2002 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 73)
    - St. Louis Encephalitis -- Letter, 1999 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 74)
    - Toxic Chemicals and Quality of Life Information Packet, Undated (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 75)
    - Training Program for Health Professionals, Greater Boston Physicians for Social Responsibility, 2001 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 76)
    - Volatile Organic Compounds [VOCs] and MCS, 1995; 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 77)
    - West Nile Virus -- DEET, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 78)
    - West Nile Virus -- Draft of New York State West Nile Virus Response Plan and Notes, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 79)
    - West Nile Virus -- New York State Department of Health, Draft West Nile Virus Response Plan, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 80)
    - West Nile Virus Meeting -- New York State Department of Health, New York State West Nile Virus-Response Plan, draft, 2001 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 81)
    - West Nile Virus -- Notes from Meeting with Albany County Department of Health Commissioner, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 82)
    - West Nile Virus -- Notes from Meeting with NY Attorney General Office, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 83)
    - West Nile Virus -- Public Meeting, Town of Colony, NY, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 84)
    - West Nile Virus -- Schenectady Department of Health Meeting, 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 85)
    - West Nile Virus -- Senate Field Hearing, 1999 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 86)
    - West Nile Virus -- Testimony before the New York City Council Oversight Hearing, Encephalitis Outbreak, 1999 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 87)
    - West Nile Virus -- "Toward Safer Mosquito Control in New York", 2000 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 88)
    - World Wildlife Fund / The Global Toxic Chemicals Initiative, Addressing the Threat of Toxic Contamination to Life on Earth, 2001-2002 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 89)
    - Maternal Infant Network -- Pesticide Free Pregnancy Project Brochure, 1998 (Box 4 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 1)
    - Maternal Infant Network -- Reviewer Comments for Pesticide-Free Pregnancy Project, 1997 (Box 4 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 2)
    - Multiple Chemical Sensitivity -- Newsletter Resources, 1993; 1996 (Box 4 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 3)
    - Multiple Chemical sensitivity Booklet, MCS in the Workplace Taskforce / NYCAP, 1992-2002 (Box 4 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 4)
  - Subseries 4: Occupational Issues, Undated; 5.4
    This subseries documents NYCAP's involvement in workplace safety and health issues particularly, but not exclusively, its work on the Occupational Safety and Health Training and Education Program (OSHTEP). This was a New York State Department of Labor funded program that made up an important portion of NYCAP's budget. NYCAP held numerous training conferences in connection with this program, the main goals of which were to educate workers about proper pest control methods, the health issues and risks of pesticides used in the workplace, along with low-risk pest control alternatives, and workers rights / employers responsibilities.
    - Blueprint for Prevention -- A Guide to Preventing Chemical Releases, 1989 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 1)
    - Building 8 -- Indoor Air Pollution Issues at New York State Government Buildings [1 of 2], 1987-2001 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 2)
    - California Health and Safety Committees, 1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 3)
    - California Health and Safety Grants, 1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 4)
    - Chemical Sensitivity on the Job, Specific Cases, 1986; 1989-1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 5)
    - Council on Occupational Safety and Health [COSH], 1989-1991; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 6)
    - electromagnetic Fields Workbook, Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 7)
    - Environmental Health Network / Louisiana Injured Workers' Union, Job Damaged People" A Handbook for Survival After the Injury, 1993 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 8)
    - "Fact Sheet for Exterminators" -- New York State Occupational Safety and Health Training and Education Program, 1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 9)
    - Fact Sheets for Exterminators, Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 10)
    - Farm Occupational Safety and Health, 1985-1996 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 11)
    - Farmworker Justice Fund, the Occupational Health of Migrant and Seasonal Farmworkers in the United States, 1988-1989 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 12)
    - Indoor Air Quality News Clippings, 1987-1988; 1992-1995; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 13)
    - Labor and Pesticides / PANNA, Notes, 1992 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 14)
    - Labor and the Environment / western MassCOSH, Presentation and Report, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 15)
    - Labor Issues on the Job, 1989; 1994-1995; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 16)
    - Material safety Data Sheets, 1983; 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 17)
    - National Executive Housekeepers Association, Inc. Programs, 1992 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 18)
    - New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health, "SafetyRep", 1995 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 19)
    - New York State, Dept. of Labor, Occupational Injuries and Illnesses Surveys, 1992-1996 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 20)
    - New York State Labor and Environmental Network, 1992-1995 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 21)
    - New York State Public Employees Safety and Health Act [PESH] -- NYCAP Comments on Pesticide Standards, 1985-1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 22)
    - New York State Public Employees Safety and Health Act [PESH] / Right to Know Law -- Publications and Notes, 1980-1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 23)
    - NYCAP Occupational Health Training Project Grant Proposal to OSHTEP -- Support Letters, 1995 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 24)
    - NYCAP Project Summary and Grant Application Cover Sheet, DOL/OSHTEP, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 25)
    - Occupational Health and Safety Articles / Handouts, 1985-1992; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 26)
    - Occupational Health and Safety -- Educational Materials, 1986-1995 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 27)
    - Occupational Health and Safety Programs, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 28)
    - Occupational Health Program, Sample Letters, Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 29)
    - Occupational Health Services, Inc., Company Information Packet on MSDS, Software, 1992 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 30)
    - Occupational Pesticide Exposure / NYS Right to Know Law, 1990-1995; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 31)
    - Occupational Safety, Pamphlets, 1991; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 32)
    - Occupational Safety and Health Resource List for Eastern New York, 1997 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 33)
    - OSHA Reform Committee / New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health, 1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 34)
    - OSHTEP -- 1996 Contract Status Report (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 35)
    - OSHTEP Contract -- Financial Information, 1997 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 36)
    - OSHTEP Contract -- FY 1997-98 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 37)
    - OSHTEP Contractors -- List, Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 38)
    - OSHTEP Event Rosters, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 39)
    - OSHTEP Grant Denial, Appeals and Support Letters, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 40)
    - OSHTEP Grant Development -- Marilyn DuBois, 1995 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 41)
    - OSHTEP Grant [FY 1997-98] -- Preparation Materials, 1995-1996 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 42)
    - OSHTEP Grant Project -- Modification Notes, 1996 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 43)
    - OSHTEP Grant Project [FY 1997-1998]- Support Letters, 1996 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 44)
    - OSHTEP Grant Proposal, FY, 1998-1999; 1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 45)
    - OSHTEP Grants -- Request for Proposal [REP] Notes, 1999 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 46)
    - OSHTEP Grants, DOL Financial Reporting, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 47)
    - OSHTEP Grants -- List of 1996 Recipients, 1995 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 48)
    - OSHTEP Outreach -- All events, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 49)
    - OSHTEP Program Evaluations, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 50)
    - OSHTEP Project, NYS Dept. of Labor [DOL] / Hazard Abatement Board [HAB], 1998 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 1)
    - OSHTEP Training Events -- Planning and Expenses, 1997-1998 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 2)
    - Onions and Pesticides / Farmworker Pesticide Education, 1997-2000 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 3)
    - Pesticides in the Workplace Information Sheets, 1992; Undated (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 4)
    - Pesticides on the Job: Workers' Rights and Employers' Responsibilities, 1992 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 5)
    - Pesticides on the Job: Workers' Rights and Employers' Responsibilities, Update and Supporting Information, 1997 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 6)
    - Right To Know / MSDS, 1987-1995; Undated (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 7)
    - Tessler, Jamie [Occupational Safety and Health Consultant] -- NYCAP Contract, Cleaning Chemical Fact Sheets, IPM Curriculum, 1994-1995 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 8)
    - Worker Safety Issues, 1995; Undated (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 9)
    - Worker's Compensation Guides and References, 1993-1994; Undated (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 10)
    - Workshop Exercise and Examples, Undated (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 11)
    - Building 8 -- Indoor Air Pollution Issues at New York State Government Buildings [2 of 2], 1987-2001 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 1)
    - Occupational Safety and Health Advocacy, 1988-1994 (Box 3 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 2)
  - Subseries 5: Rights-of-way (ROW), Undated; 5.5
    The main concern reflected in these materials was weed control on roadside and utility rights-of-way (ROW), and NYCAP's advocacy and research on alternatives to herbicides for this purpose.
    - Central Hudson Gas and Electric Company -- Rights-of-Way Herbicide Use, 1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 1)
    - Cornell Local Roads Program / Nuggets and Nibbles, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 2)
    - Institute of Ecosystem Studies, "Vegetation Dynamics Along Utility Rights-of-Way", ca. 1990 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 3)
    - Integrated Roadside Vegetation Management [IRVM] -- Iowa Example, 1990-1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 4)
    - Integrated Vegetation Management [IVM], How-to Articles, 1985-1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 5)
    - New York Power Authority, Collection of Utility Right-of-Way [Row] Vegetation Management Materials, 2001 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 6)
    - New York State Electric and Gas Corporation [NYSEG] -- Rights-of-Way Herbicide Use, 1983-2002 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 7)
    - New York State Electric and Gas -- Proposed Seneca Lake Storage Project and Pipeline, 1995-1996 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 8)
    - New York State Public Service Commission, Utility Rights of Way, 1977-1996 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 9)
    - Niagara Mohawk Power Co. right-of-Way Herbicide Use, 1978-1992 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 10)
    - Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation -- Herbicides and Right-of-Way Management Workshop, 1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 11)
    - Orange and Rockland Utilities / Right of Way [ROW] Herbicide Use, 1991-1993 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 12)
    - Railroad Rights of Way [ROW], 1986-1993 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 13)
    - Right-of-Way [ROW] Contact List, 1992 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 14)
    - Rights-of-Way, Articles from Around the U.S. and Notes, 1984-1999 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 15)
    - Rights-of-Way Management for Utilities, Part 84 of NYS Public Service Law [16 NYCRR], 1997-1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 16)
    - Rights-of-Way Vegetation Management -- Herbicide Alternatives, 1974-1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 17)
    - Roadside Pesticide Spraying in Putnam, New York -- Correspondence, Press and Collected Information on Pesticides, 1989-1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 18)
    - Roadside Pesticide Use -- National, Articles and Correspondence, 1984-1995 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 19)
    - Roadside Right of Way: Activist's Toolkit, 1991-2002 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 20)
    - Roadside Right of Way: Alternatives to Herbicides, 1994-2001 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 21)
    - Roadside Right of Way: Herbicide Hazards, 1982-1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 22)
    - Roadside Right of Way: Native Plants, 1990-1997; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 23)
    - Roadside Right of Way Network, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 24)
    - Roadside Rights-of-Way -- Maine, 1982-1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 25)
    - Roadside Rights-of-Way -- Massachusetts, 1980-1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 26)
    - Roadside Rights-of-Way -- New Hampshire, 1986-1991 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 27)
    - Roadside Rights-of-Way -- Vermont, 1991; 1994; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 28)
    - Roadside Vegetation Management Articles, 1990-1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 29)
    - Town of Ulysses / Agro-Statistics, Roadside Pesticide Use Investigation, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 30)
    - Washington State Department of Transportation, Integrated Vegetation Management for Roadsides, 1997 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 31)
    - Washington State Department of Transportation, What Is Integrated Vegetation Management?, 1997 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 32)
  - Subseries 6: School / IPM, Undated; 5.6
    This subseries contains materials on Integrated Pest Mangagement (IPM), a method of pest control that NYCAP advocated. IPM is defined as "the coordinated use of pest and environmental information with available pest control methods to prevent unacceptable levels of pest damage by the most economical means and with the least possible hazard to people, property, and the environment" [http://www.epa.gov/pesticides/food/ipm.htm]. Most of the materials are centered around schools, particularly the Health Schools Network (HSN). Materials about pesticide / chemical use and related issues in schools, which are not primarily about IPM, are also included. This subseries has been divided into two additional subseries, one consisting of school-related materials, and the other IPM-related materials in other institutions.
    A. Schools.
    B. IPM in Other Institutions.
    - Albany Service Corps. / Pest Control Through Integrated Pest Management Contract, 1996-1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 1)
    - Community IPM Coordinating Council Meeting, 2001 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 2)
    - Community IPM Coordinating Council Meeting, 2002 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 3)
    - Department of Environment Conservation Integrated Pest Management Program, Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 4)
    - Integrated Pest Management for Health Care Facilities, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 5)
    - Integrated Pest Management in Building, Policies and Programs, 1991-1993; Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 6)
    - Integrated Pest Management in New York City, 1993-1995 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 7)
    - Integrated Pest Management -- Information Resources, 1994 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 8)
    - Integrated Pest Management [IPM] -- Policies and Implementation, 1992-1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 9)
    - Integrated Pest Management Program Fact Sheets, Undated (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 10)
    - IPM for Archives and Libraries, ca. 2000 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 11)
    - IPM for Healthcare Facilities -- Syracuse, 1997 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 12)
    - IPM for Health Care Facilities Training Conference, Program Evaluations, Albany, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 13)
    - IPM in New York State -- 10 year Review drafts, 1997-2001 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 1)
    - IPM -- U.S. National Arboretum, 1993-1994; Undated (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 2)
    - IPM Workbook for New York State Schools -- [Binder Contents], 1998 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 3)
    - Least -- Toxic Pest Management Programs, 1991-1992; 1994; Undated (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 4)
    - Modern Pest Control Techniques -- A Generalists Guide to Integrated Pest Management, 1992 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 5)
    - National Park Service -- "Scorpions and Spiders", IPM Information Package, 1984 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 6)
    - New York State Attorney General, Pest Management in New York State Hospitals, 1995 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 7)
    - New York State, Community IPM Stakeholders, 2001 (Box 2 (5-Programs, Distributed Information and Miscellaneou), Folder 8)